[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ce", "question": "Where was Enrico Caruso born?", "answer": "Naples, Italy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4af", "question": "What year did The Amritsar Massacre take place?", "answer": "1919", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d1", "question": "What year did tennis player Martina Navratilova turn pro?", "answer": "1975", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3233a9bf195a31e15d739c", "question": "Whose head was given to Herod's wife on a plate?", "answer": "John the Baptist", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a65c", "question": "The port city of Sandusky is located in which state?", "answer": "Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c25", "question": "Who wrote the book \"One Fish, Two Fish, Red Fish, Blue Fish\"?", "answer": "Dr. Seuss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a014", "question": "What actor was the narrator in the movie \"A.I.: Artificial Intelligence\"?", "answer": "Ben Kingsley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523c45736d4be723796b36", "question": "What is the name of the highway that travels through all ten Canadian provinces?", "answer": "Trans-Canada Highway, or Route Transcanadienne", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c26e", "question": "What is May's birthstone?", "answer": "Emerald", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cde1fe347d002c297e4f9", "question": "Who wrote the classic science fiction trilogy \"Helliconia\"?", "answer": "Brian W. Aldiss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ca", "question": "Who authored the famous poem \"The Charge of the Light Brigade\"?", "answer": "Alfred, Lord Tennyson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a820", "question": "What river forms much of the border between Washington and Oregon?", "answer": "Columbia River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4ddb406d333868d34d707", "question": "Who was known as the \"Mad Monarch\"?", "answer": "George III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a552373e1c6f9840ba3193", "question": "What color flag indicates a fair throw in the shot put?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e9a43ebfabb9c85d8a979", "question": "The meat pie, Tourtiere, originated in which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab960b86faa38a764be51b", "question": "What former republic did the Trabant originate from?", "answer": "East Germany, or German Democratic Republic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4ee2406d333868d34d774", "question": "What lobster organ is made into a delicacy known as \"tomalley\"?", "answer": "Liver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef32ed6ce05a3942286e00", "question": "How many U.S. states are needed to ratify an amendment for it to become part of the constitution?", "answer": "Three-fourths", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96cdd23c87fd04dd15e29", "question": "Who was the first tennis player to win the Grand Slam?", "answer": "Don Budge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b1", "question": "Quito is the capital of which South American country?", "answer": "Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aae6", "question": "Accra is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Ghana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133890b", "question": "What ballet term translates literally as \"in Arabic fashion\"?", "answer": "Arabesque", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015ded5fe83fe1f2a824b72", "question": "What war lasted from June 25, 1950 to July 27, 1953?", "answer": "Korean War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339744", "question": "What album earned the Dixie Chicks a Grammy Award in 2007?", "answer": "Taking the Long Way", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cfd", "question": "In which movie did Veronica Lake portray a witch?", "answer": "I Married a Witch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c47a", "question": "In what year was the Toyota Prius hybrid car first commercially sold?", "answer": "1997", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f1693bf7c52aae91cc07ce", "question": "What year did Wilkie Collins publish the novel \"The Moonstone\"?", "answer": "1868", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d11", "question": "In \"The Farmer in the Dell\", what stands alone?", "answer": "The cheese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba92", "question": "What puzzle toy, invented in Hungary, was the best-\u00adselling toy of 1981?", "answer": "Rubik\u2019s Cube", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f65", "question": "How many camels carried the 117,000 volumes of Abdul Kassem Ismael's library?", "answer": "400", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a16d", "question": "Which Alan Parker film dealt with racial murders in America?", "answer": "Mississippi Burning", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c19a", "question": "The \"canebrake\", \"timber\" and \"pygmy\" are types of what?", "answer": "Rattlesnakes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be29", "question": "What January 6, 1994, act got Shane Shant a four-year prison sentence?", "answer": "Kneecapping Nancy Kerrigan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b30301dd7bf43be5e7a6", "question": "What flower symbolizes indifference according to the Old Farmer\u2019s Almanac?", "answer": "Candytuft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf6", "question": "The infamous Pez dispenser was first patented in what year?", "answer": "1952", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8aad401dd7bf43be5e762", "question": "Which Thanksgiving favorite did Marcus L. Urann invent?", "answer": "Cranberry sauce", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b2", "question": "When did the Jallianwahla Bagh massacre take place?", "answer": "April 13, 1919", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af13", "question": "What city hosted the Winter Olympics in 1932?", "answer": "Lake Placid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e5f0d60d274615ecf514532", "question": "What U.S. President's family home was known as the \"Sherwood Forest Plantation\"?", "answer": "John Tyler", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5be57ee45415ba52ed6f0aa7", "question": "For which brand was Michael Jackson shooting a commercial for when his hair caught on fire?", "answer": "Pepsi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c776", "question": "What type of animal flew to space in the US V2 rocket launched in 1949?", "answer": "A monkey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca34", "question": "What geological period followed the Jurassic?", "answer": "Cretaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cd6dbe347d002c297e4bd", "question": "\"Diamants sur canap\u00e9\" is the French translation of what American film?", "answer": "Breakfast at Tiffany's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d6", "question": "Someone who is polytheistic believes in more than one what?", "answer": "God", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133999a", "question": "On what street do TV's \"Desperate Housewives\" live?", "answer": "Wisteria Lane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd69f486c0f9723ab15cb29", "question": "Who was the first woman to win the Pulitzer Prize?", "answer": "Edith Wharton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b2cc01dd7bf43be5e7a3", "question": "What did Mae Jemison, the first African-American woman to go to space, study while in medical school?", "answer": "Modern dance", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ae866977f28483af1e7fdd4", "question": "What is the name of the musician best known for his 1993 song \"What is Love\"?", "answer": "Haddaway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69aab20565ad31a57c756", "question": "In the Bible, who is the wife of Boaz?", "answer": "Ruth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a9", "question": "Who considered founding a utopian art colony at Arles in France prior to his suicide?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec83eaec223966ae8f87fa", "question": "The musical group 3T are all relatives of which legendary pop musician?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a69", "question": "For what 1997 film did Kim Basinger win a Best Supporting Actress Oscar?", "answer": "L.A. Confidential", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a1", "question": "What country is named for the founder of the \"Friars Preachers\" religious order?", "answer": "The Dominican Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab13f6baab681b09292170", "question": "What car manufacturer was the first to mass-produce and equip a production vehicle with a V4 engine?", "answer": "Lancia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a44", "question": "What author created the characters Ponyboy and Sodapop?", "answer": "S.E. Hinton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90d", "question": "Who lost part of his ear to the teeth of Mike Tyson in 1997?", "answer": "Evander Holyfield", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aace", "question": "What is the capital of Brazil?", "answer": "Brasilia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133903c", "question": "Which musical term denotes that a piece is to be played \"very sweetly\"?", "answer": "Dolcissimo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef66956ce05a3942286e79", "question": "Which musician was the original \"Thomas the Tank Engine\" narrator on TV?", "answer": "Ringo Starr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339353", "question": "For how many years was the \"The Mary Tyler Moore Show\" on air?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedd8e66ce05a3942286d76", "question": "What was the nationality of Chief Bromden in the film \"One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest\"?", "answer": "Native American", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf8", "question": "Who wrote \"Uncle Tom's Cabin\"?", "answer": "Harriet Beecher Stowe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff2102531a458464a93c43c", "question": "What classic novel was originally published with the title \"Fiesta\" in the U.K.?", "answer": "\"The Sun Also Rises", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339699", "question": "Which movie gave us the line \"You talkin' to me?\"", "answer": "Taxi Driver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf36", "question": "In Germany, where would you be if you were in a \"Krankenhaus\"?", "answer": "Hospital", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6012185063c99d48cd169af0", "question": "In Florida, only on Sundays, it is illegal for a single woman to do what?", "answer": "Skydive", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c0", "question": "In The Simpsons, who is Cletus, the slack-jawed yokel married to?", "answer": "Brandine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b32a", "question": "Florence Nightingale tended the soldiers in which war?", "answer": "Crimean", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c89d11011619dd6d415482", "question": "While pretending to be an inner city calculus teacher, what was Eric Cartman\u2019s catch phrase in South Park?", "answer": "How do I reach these keeeds?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133962e", "question": "What TV character sings the song \"Smelly Cat\"?", "answer": "Phoebe Buffay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db77380ab2c8f322317fec", "question": "In which country was Dominion Day celebrated until 1982?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc4a", "question": "What item of clothing was Ralph Lauren's first product?", "answer": "A necktie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc727ec223966ae8f888b", "question": "What is the name of the device used to facilitate dream sharing in the movie \"Inception\"?", "answer": "A Portable Automated Somnacin IntraVenous Device (PASIV)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f565d333a95c66dc4fe75b", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"The Turn of the Screw\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Britten", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b323727bf195a31e15d73c2", "question": "Who directed the 1980 film \"Ordinary People\"?", "answer": "Robert Redford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339db5", "question": "In 2007, which comedian jumped from the roof of Cannes' Carlton Hotel wearing a giant bee costume?", "answer": "Jerry Seinfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c40", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what field does Carl Carlson have a master's degree in?", "answer": "Nuclear Physics", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133935f", "question": "What was in the jaws of the swordfish mounted on the wall in the Addams Family house?", "answer": "A human leg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d03", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Barney Fife?", "answer": "Sheriff Andy Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe7", "question": "How many players are in a Polo team?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febba227e83c707845b2143", "question": "How much was spent producing the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "An estimated $25 million", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1c", "question": "What name did Superman have on Krypton?", "answer": "Kal-El", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a84d", "question": "What sea borders Iran to the north?", "answer": "Caspian Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa5926ce05a3942286ec3", "question": "Which actor had a role in Madonna's music video \"Papa Don't Preach\"?", "answer": "Danny Aiello", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c312", "question": "The popular caterpillar sushi roll features unagi, the Japanese word for what type of sea creature?", "answer": "Eel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ded", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"lollipop\"?", "answer": "Romany", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8b4", "question": "In what city would you find Stanley Park?", "answer": "Vancouver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59bb2a1ac9bff04efae6d75c", "question": "Which UK band had a No. 1 hit in 1965 with their song \"I'm Alive\"?", "answer": "The Hollies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc7e", "question": "What Sanskrit word do Buddhists use to refer to the endless cycle of birth, death, and rebirth?", "answer": "Samsara", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e8f7fe83fe1f2a824be2", "question": "Which monarch appointed Pitt the Younger to the office of prime minister in December 1783?", "answer": "George III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63f", "question": "What is the top speed a freefalling object can reach called?", "answer": "Terminal Velocity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5c", "question": "Who painted the world famous \"Mona Lisa\"?", "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b494", "question": "Which country hosted the 1900 Olympic Games?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a83d", "question": "In the first Punic War, Rome and Carthage fought over possession of what Mediterranean island?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc1461469bb8041d07a087", "question": "What is the primary flavoring agent of a Greek Tzatziki sauce?", "answer": "Garlic", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65934ae7e414034b5aefc", "question": "What killer was known as the \"Vampire of Dusseldorf\"?", "answer": "Peter Kurten", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa1d", "question": "Jefferson City is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b7ffb133a3a814d89068c61", "question": "The US made \"Medium Tank, M4\" is better known as what?", "answer": "The Sherman tank", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b055", "question": "For what crime was Al Capone finally sent to prison for in 1931?", "answer": "Tax evasion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984b", "question": "The music duo \"Daft Punk\" consists of which two French musicians?", "answer": "Thomas Bangalter and Guy-Manuel de Homem-Christo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d47", "question": "What folk hero is said to live in the Sherwood Forest?", "answer": "Robin Hood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c208", "question": "What year was the UK an Olympic Games host for the first time?", "answer": "1908", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b320", "question": "Who became prime minister of Cuba in 1959?\u00a0", "answer": "Fidel Castro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c11e", "question": "Harvey Lee Yeary became famous under what name?", "answer": "Lee Majors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd9", "question": "What was the only place Tandy's popular TRS-80 computers were sold?", "answer": "RadioShack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7358ceec85e375820b24d", "question": "Who said, \"Success is the ability to go from one failure to another with no loss of enthusiasm.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ec", "question": "In which movie did Edward James Olmos get a group of inner-city kids to learn calculus?", "answer": "Stand and Deliver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523dc2736d4be723796b47", "question": "What year did the last Province or Territory join Canada?", "answer": "1999", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59da1bc3f6756c9b30ba14fd", "question": "Graham Kerr became famous under what nickname?", "answer": "The Galloping Gourmet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c1f", "question": "What year was artist, Sting, born?", "answer": "1951", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eff", "question": "What famous horse belonged to Dudley Do-Right?", "answer": "Horse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338904", "question": "What form of theater was the subject of many of Degas' paintings?", "answer": "Ballet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59049f03cf93664eb10486b7", "question": "What US state is home to the \"One Shell Square\" skyscraper?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a527", "question": "Whidbey Island is the largest island in which state?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f1", "question": "In 1917, Finland declared its independence from what country?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e6bcfe83fe1f2a824bd1", "question": "Who gave Queen Elizabeth I the soubriquet \"Gloriana\"?", "answer": "Edmund Spenser, in his epic poem \"The Faerie Queene\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe734b0eec85e375820b23b", "question": "Who was the architect of the \"Final Solution\"?", "answer": "Heinrich Himmler", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a109", "question": "Who does Fred Savage play on the TV show \"The Wonder Years\"?", "answer": "Kevin Arnold", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d9", "question": "What island nation was ruled by \"Papa Doc\" and \"Baby Doc\" Duvalier?", "answer": "Haiti", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "596df8c6f0cc2631d16a3c62", "question": "Crazy Horse and Sitting Bull were born in which US state?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afe4", "question": "What colony was established by the passengers of the Mayflower?", "answer": "Plymouth Colony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934b", "question": "Who was the first host of \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Steve Allen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b42601dd7bf43be5e7bc", "question": "What company was formerly named Cadabra Inc.?", "answer": "Amazon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071ded3745b36be73039df", "question": "What is the name of the first Lunar Module to land on the Moon?", "answer": "Eagle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa7", "question": "Honshu is the largest island of which country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb95", "question": "Since 1909, what women's magazine has guaranteed its advertiser\u2019s products with a \"seal of approval\"?", "answer": "Good Housekeeping", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b7e", "question": "Who wrote Ulysses?", "answer": "James Joyce", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b7ff9513a3a814d89068c53", "question": "What is Ethiopia's official language?", "answer": "Amharic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff6690552a821ff76ae8b08", "question": "Who renamed the U.S. presidential yacht \"Honey Fritz,\" in honor of his grandfather, a former Boston mayor?", "answer": "President John F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff6685052a821ff76ae8b03", "question": "Around what sea did Jesus call His first apostles?", "answer": "Christ first saw Peter and Andrew close to the Sea of Galilee. He beseeched them to follow Him.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339431", "question": "Who both wrote and starred in the 1996 movie \"From Dusk Till Dawn\"?", "answer": "Quentin Tarantino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e8", "question": "What year were X-rays discovered?", "answer": "1895", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133893a", "question": "Who painted the Sistine Chapel ceiling?", "answer": "Michelangelo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af30", "question": "From what terrible disease did Robert the Bruce suffer?", "answer": "Leprosy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a40d", "question": "Devil's Island, once the world's most notorious penal colony, is located off the coast of what country?", "answer": "French Guiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339321", "question": "In the movie \"Hangover\", what name did Alan use to refer to his circle of friends?", "answer": "The wolf pack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067ce0ff9c0647b50a8070", "question": "What is the name of the sixth expansion to the World of Warcraft game universe?", "answer": "World of Warcraft: Legion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a038", "question": "In the show \"Family Guy\", who unknowingly financed the publication of Peter's erotic novels?", "answer": "Carter Pewterschmidt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339217", "question": "What Stealers Wheel hit is heard in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Stuck in the Middle with You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a653", "question": "Which US state is nickname the \"Palmetto State\"?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e8", "question": "In what city is Jim Morrison buried?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4fa", "question": "What is the only metal that is liquid at room temperature?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b29e", "question": "What sports event did Rosie Ruiz win by cheating in 1980?", "answer": "The Boston Marathon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c818", "question": "In what part of the body would you find chyme?", "answer": "The stomach", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a571", "question": "Which US state is home to North Cascades National Park?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b227", "question": "What city was Medgar Evens killed in?", "answer": "Jackson, Mississippi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a242", "question": "At the end of the TV series \"M*A*S*H\", what character stayed in Korea?", "answer": "Maxwell Q. Klinger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3bc5ff048f679a45ab37", "question": "What kind of plant stem is soft and green?", "answer": "Herbaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f4f301dd7bf43be5e826", "question": "What is the point at which two lines meet to form an angle?", "answer": "Vertex", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a504", "question": "What are the four longest rivers in the world?", "answer": "Nile, Amazon, Yangtze, Huang Ho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b01f", "question": "What was the last name of husband and wife Julius and Ethel, executed for treason in 1953?", "answer": "Rosenberg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7e805b24f84e0b9f9ffc2", "question": "Perth is the capital of which Australian state?", "answer": "Western Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f40e01dd7bf43be5e81d", "question": "DIY stands for what?", "answer": "Do It Yourself", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ff", "question": "What decade was the first Indianapolis 500 race held in?", "answer": "1910s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76c52eec85e375820b2d0", "question": "Hollywood legend Clint Eastwood was once mayor of which city?", "answer": "Carmel, California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a4e", "question": "What late 1970's hit contains the following line \"Ooh, you make my motor run, my motor run\"?", "answer": "My Sharona", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3b", "question": "Who first broke the gender barrier in NASCAR racing in 1949?", "answer": "Sara Christian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c20", "question": "What is the name of Thor's hammer?", "answer": "Mjolnir", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ec2008d98002fdd633b7", "question": "Which singer's autobiography is titled \"Take It Like a Man\"?", "answer": "Boy George's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6656ca5bfecdd737e085f", "question": "What three vows do Catholic priests take?", "answer": "Poverty, chastity and obedience", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8fd3701dd7bf43be5e85b", "question": "On the internet, what does Yahoo! stand for?", "answer": "Yet Another Hierarchical Organized Oracle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4cd", "question": "What seaport's name is Spanish for \"white house\"?", "answer": "Casablanca", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e8a", "question": "What future celebrity made an appearance as Luke on \"Growing Pains\"?", "answer": "Leonardo DiCaprio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339365", "question": "30 Rock refers to what in the TV series \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "30 Rockefeller Plaza", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd809e347d002c297e4c6", "question": "In Greek mythology, who flew too close to the Sun?", "answer": "Icarus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133972d", "question": "For what 1993 movie did Anna Paquin win an Academy Award?", "answer": "The Piano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a3b06c0f9723ab15cb50", "question": "Approximately, how many Americans served in World War II?", "answer": "16 million", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60173fdc44491cbd7c5a17b7", "question": "John the Baptist's father was who?", "answer": "The father of John the Baptist was Zechariah.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f63dff048f679a45aadb", "question": "In what type of matter are atoms most tightly packed?", "answer": "Solids", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba71e874c93a3298b2161", "question": "What is Ace Frehley\u2019s persona name in the band KISS?", "answer": "Spaceman or Space Ace", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7aa", "question": "Who created the Tabasco sauce?", "answer": "Edmund McIlhenny", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b206", "question": "On what saint's day in 1572 did Catherine de Medicis have 3,000 Protestants killed in Paris?", "answer": "St. Bartholomew's Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c07e", "question": "What is equinophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Horses", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f4", "question": "What country borders both of the world's only two nations with square flags?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acf7", "question": "What was the agora in an ancient Greek city?", "answer": "Marketplace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c4a6fbde8045e484669f", "question": "Which small African mammal keeps a watch-duty rotation throughout the day?", "answer": "Meerkat -- One, called the sentry, will keep a watch for predators by standing on its hind legs.  They rotate who is on watch.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bacb", "question": "What is the International Criminal Police Organization better known as?", "answer": "Interpol", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ad", "question": "What does the \"PJ\" stand for in the name PJ Harvey?", "answer": "Polly Jean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa4a56ce05a3942286eb6", "question": "What is the name of the cat in the film \"Hocus Pocus\"?", "answer": "Thackery Binx", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c12b", "question": "What is the significance of the moth found in the Harvard Mark I computer?", "answer": "First computer \"bug\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af00", "question": "Who was the 16th president of the US?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a61d", "question": "Which US state is home to Petroglyph National Monument?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133936f", "question": "What zodiac sign is the Joker in the movie \"Batman\"?", "answer": "Pisces", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049d99cf93664eb10486af", "question": "The plane carrying what country\u2019s national rugby team crashed on Friday, October 13, 1972?", "answer": "Uruguay\u2019s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c306", "question": "Which is longer, a python or a boa constrictor?", "answer": "A python", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2a", "question": "Who opened her first school, Rome's Casa dei Bambini, in 1907?", "answer": "Maria Montessori", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec26898dc25ca9e12ef64c", "question": "How many engines are on a B-52 bomber?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ef", "question": "What flavor was the original filling in Twinkies?", "answer": "Banana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff6662a52a821ff76ae8af6", "question": "Which patriot won the acquittal of most of the British troops involved in the 1770 Boston Massacre that killed five civilians?", "answer": "John Adams (He strongly believed all people deserved a fair trial and a thorough defense.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b415", "question": "How did UN Secretary General Dag Hammarskj\u00f6ld die in September, 1961?", "answer": "In a plane crash", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f164f75f9b80650dbe7f939", "question": "Who was the first woman elected into the U.S. Congress?", "answer": "Jeannette Rankin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a962", "question": "How many territories does the US administer over?", "answer": "16", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab1177baab681b0929216c", "question": "In The Flintstones, what is the name of Barney Rubble's pet?", "answer": "Hoppy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b174377bb2d29f81593b6f4", "question": "Where do Rocky and Bullwinkle play football?", "answer": "Wossamotta U", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe766b5eec85e375820b287", "question": "Captain Henry Morgan used what island as a base of buccaneer operations?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab1b3f44fda37788a9a1dc6", "question": "Where is the Salvador Dali museum located?", "answer": "St. Petersburg, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58dba40a874c93a3298b2142", "question": "Puccini's \"Tosca\" is based on which 1887 Victorien Sardou play?", "answer": "La Tosca", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5902a0c8cad1ec93f27df770", "question": "How much larger is UK pint compared to the US pint?", "answer": "About 20%, or 95 mL", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b618", "question": "What would you find in a bento box?", "answer": "Food", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f76", "question": "What was Tom Petty's backing band?", "answer": "The Heartbreakers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ae", "question": "What name was given to textile workers who opposed modernisation during the 19th century?\u00a0", "answer": "Luddites\u00a0", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b48f849076251badbeaa9", "question": "Who won the first Nobel Prize for Medicine?", "answer": "Emil von Behring -- He discovered a diphtheria antitoxin.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f1", "question": "What Agatha Christie novel was made up of two parts - England and Egypt?", "answer": "Death on the Nile", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a286", "question": "Which 2008 film starring Seann William Scott features an epic live-action role playing battle in its climax?", "answer": "Role Models", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf1", "question": "In what year was famous designer Giorgio Armani born?", "answer": "1934", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a4", "question": "What is the longest river in Europe?", "answer": "Volga", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bad", "question": "Mitch Mitchell and Noel Redding were the two lesser-known members of what rock trio?", "answer": "Jimi Hendrix Experience", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f88201dd7bf43be5e844", "question": "What was Popeye's favorite food?", "answer": "Spinach", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ecae2b3790ded87bb38fd89", "question": "Who allegedly committed suicide in the Metropolitan Correctional Center, New York on August 10th 2019?", "answer": "Jeffrey Epstein", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96dda23c87fd04dd15e30", "question": "Who was the first U.S. Vice President to resign?", "answer": "John C. Calhoun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f1684df7c52aae91cc07c5", "question": "Selaphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Light flashes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c826", "question": "Nepetalactone is the active ingredient in what pet product?", "answer": "Catnip", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e563fe83fe1f2a824bbc", "question": "The Islamic calendar is based on which cycle?", "answer": "Lunar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff25a6431a458464a93c471", "question": "What group of animals is called a \"flink\"?", "answer": "A group of 12 or more cows", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b13c", "question": "In what year did Joseph Smith first organize the Mormon Church?", "answer": "1830", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a970b61d1b4d384d5d67f", "question": "Which Disney film marked Donald Duck's debut?", "answer": "The Wise Little Hen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a2d", "question": "What does Peppermint Patty always call Charlie Brown in the \"Peanuts\" cartoon strip?", "answer": "Chuck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59067c20ff9c0647b50a806a", "question": "What mountain range does the Gotthard Base Tunnel pass through?", "answer": "The Alps", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecd25aec223966ae8f88c4", "question": "What was the first full-length film from director Steve McQueen that did not have a one word title?", "answer": "\"12 Years a Slave\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339977", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Lenny has a master's degree in what field?", "answer": "Nuclear Physics", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d2", "question": "What decade were golf carts introduced in the US?", "answer": "1940s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4cc", "question": "What day did the Battle of the Somme end?", "answer": "November 18, 1916", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c854", "question": "What nation is home to the Komodo dragon?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff51544ff04d658268c92e9", "question": "What countries were involved in the Wars of the Three Kingdoms?", "answer": "The Wars of the Three Kingdoms, aka British Civil Wars, took place in\u00a0England, Ireland and Scotland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff214fe31a458464a93c45b", "question": "Who came up with \"The Allegory of the Cave\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be8", "question": "The TV show \"Seinfeld\" is a show about what?", "answer": "Nothing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b203", "question": "What metal item on the end of a kite string gave off the sparks in Benjamin Franklin's 1752 experiment?", "answer": "A key", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339158", "question": "What popular artist sang the words: \"I'm afraid of Americans\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c77cdd024f0f7a362efd543", "question": "Who was the captain of the Bonhomme Richard in the 18th Century??", "answer": "John Paul Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5904a0d8cf93664eb10486ba", "question": "The \"Ugu Youth\" radio station is broadcast in which African country?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1bc", "question": "Jello Biafra was the lead singer for which American punk band?", "answer": "The Dead Kennedys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69b7220565ad31a57c75f", "question": "What English code breaker created a machine that helped to decrypt Nazi messages?", "answer": "Alan Turing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a5e", "question": "Jazz musicians sometimes refer to which instrument as a \"licorice stick\"?", "answer": "Clarinet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b66f01dd7bf43be5e7dc", "question": "Queen Elizabeth technically owns thousands of what kind of animal?", "answer": "Swans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c3c", "question": "Who wrote the play \"Long Day's Journey Into Night\"?", "answer": "Eugene O'Neill", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c98", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Stuckeyville, Ohio?", "answer": "Ed", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b943364247bf200fb88a", "question": "Who popularized the song \"A Boy Named Sue\" in 1969?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c660", "question": "What is the purpose of \"seeding\" a cloud?", "answer": "To create rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f7a", "question": "What was Jonathan Richman's backing band?", "answer": "The Modern Lovers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0b", "question": "Who won a Pulitzer Prize for his novel \"The Old Man and the Sea\"?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c76c", "question": "What explorer introduced chickens to the New World?", "answer": "Christopher Columbus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98d", "question": "What part of a piano's action permits the keys to be struck in quick repetition?", "answer": "Escapement", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a89e", "question": "What islands are home to most of the world's blue-footed boobies?", "answer": "The Galapagos Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa3acfc73aa70ea0b70ae1", "question": "What is the highest waterfall in Europe?", "answer": "The\u00a0Krimml Waterfalls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b869", "question": "What kind of beans are dropped into a Sambuca?", "answer": "Coffee beans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ce", "question": "What is the sternum more commonly known as?", "answer": "Breastbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a007", "question": "What city's music scene gave us R.E.M., Danger Mouse, and the B-52s?", "answer": "Athens, Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb81", "question": "What Christian denomination was begun by John Wesley in 1738?", "answer": "Methodist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcdf", "question": "Which is the lightest of the three kinds of fencing swords?", "answer": "The foil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0db", "question": "What does the Latin word \"Verbatim\" translate into?", "answer": "Word for word", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c17", "question": "What year was the TV show \"SpongeBob SquarePants\" first aired in?", "answer": "1999", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae9e", "question": "What did the 1944 education act raise the school leaving age to in the UK?", "answer": "15", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339011", "question": "Which famous painting was stolen from an Oslo museum in 1994?", "answer": "The Scream", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6002414f4be4723ccac22175", "question": "Who was the leader of the wolves in \"The Jungle Book\"?", "answer": "Akala", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b155", "question": "What year was Princess Diana born?", "answer": "1961", "category": "history"}]